sportlobster.com 2016-04-08

# Sportlobster

Last updated: October 2015

##### 1\. INFORMATION ABOUT US

Welcome to Sportlobster [www.sportlobster.com](https://www.sportlobster.com/) (“Sportlobster”) and Emirates Sportlobster [sportlobster.emirates.com](https://sportlobster.emirates.com/) (“Emirates Sportlobster”) (together “our sites”), the sport social network where fans of all sports can get real time information, news and social interactions tailored to their passions in sport.

Whether it's a status update, a comment, a prediction or an article that you use to express your opinion, the world will have access to it just as you'll have access to those of other users.

Our sites are operated and owned by Sportlobster Ltd whose registered address is 4th floor, 36 Spital Square, London E1 6DY with registration number 08100720 (“we, us or our”). Our branding partner for EmiratesSportlobster is Emirates, a corporation established by Dubai Ruler’s Decree No. 2 of 1985 (as amended) having its principal office at Emirates Group Headquarters, Airport Road, P.O. Box 686, Dubai, United Arab Emirates. **Both ourselves and our partners take your privacy very seriously and are committed to protecting and respecting it.**

This Privacy and Cookies Policy (together with the documents referred to on it and the Terms and Conditions) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, either though our sites or email notifications, applications, buttons and widgets (the services), will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

In respect of any use of [www.sportlobster.com](https://www.sportlobster.com/), for the purposes of the UK Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the data controller is Sportlobster Ltd of 4th floor, 36 Spital Square, London, E1 6DY

In respect of any use of [sportlobster.emirates.com](https://sportlobster.emirates.com/), for the purposes of the UK Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”) we are the data controller, except where our partner Emirates provides us with specific instructions on processing or process the information in their own business in which case we may be joint data controllers with Emirates. We will only collect and process information about you in accordance with this Privacy and Cookies Policy. By using our sites and other services, you consent to such processing.

##### 2\. INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

We know how important your privacy is to you, and it's important to us that you feel safe and secure on our sites and other services. We want to make sure that you have the very best experience of our sites and other services and so we may sometimes ask you for certain information and you may send personal data to us. We may collect and process the following data about you:

Information that you provide when you fill in forms on our sites, such as your name, username, password, date of birth, address, email address, gender and location. Some of this information, for example, your name and username, is listed publicly on our sites and services, including on your profile page and in search results. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our sites and/or services.

Additional information when you provide us with profile information to make public, such as a micro biography, your website, or a picture. You may provide further information to customize your account. _Your account settings control whether others can find you by your email address._

Information about you such as your name, address and contact details when you enter a competition or prize-draw we may choose to operate.

_If you connect your Sportlobster account to your account on another service in order to cross-post between our sites and that service, the other service may send us your registration or profile information on that service and other information that you authorize_.

Information of your location in your posts and in your profile.

If you contact us, we may keep a record of your message, email address and contact information.

We or our agents on our behalf may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

_Details of your visits to our sites including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access_.

##### 3\. PUBLIC INFORMATION

Most of the information you provide us is information you are asking us to make public. This includes not only content you post and the metadata provided with the posts, such as when you posted, but also the lists you create, the people you follow, the posts you mark as favourites that result from your use of our sites and services. Our default is almost always to make the information you provide public for as long as you do not delete it from our sites and services, but we may give you settings to make the information generally more private if you want. This can be altered in your Profile Visibility in Account Settings. Your public information is broadly and instantly disseminated. For instance, _  your public user profile information and public posts may be searchable by search engines_. **When you share information or content like photos, videos, and links via our sites, you should consider carefully the information you are making public**.

##### 4\. IP ADDRESSES AND COOKIES

We use analytics to collect and store anonymous statistical data about our users' visits to our sites and services.

We may also collect information about your computer, mobile phone (or other portable or static device used to access our sites and services) and your visit to our sites, including where available your IP address, operating system, session_id, login, screen name and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our partners and if necessary our advertisers.

We may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file and/or similar tools which are stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive to report back anonymous data to us. They help us to improve our sites and to deliver a better and more personalised service.

Our sites use the following cookies:

##### 4.1 Google Analytics and AdWords Conversion

This web analytics and conversion service provided by Google Inc helps us to analyse how users use our sites. It counts the number of visitors and tells us things about their behaviour overall, such as typical length of stay on our sites or the average number of pages a user views and whether they have clicked on ads.

This information generated by the cookie about your use of our sites will be transmitted to and stored by Google on their servers. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of our sites, compiling reports on website activity and providing other services relating to website activity.

Generally, cookies may be used to enable us:

To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.

To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our sites according to your individual interests and provide a more personalised experience to you.

To speed up your searches.

To recognise you when you return to our sites.

Some third party cookies are set by services that appear on our sites. They are set by the operators of that service and are not in our control. They may be set by Twitter, Facebook, Pinterest, Tumblr, Instagram and other third party services and relate to the ability of users to share content on our sites.

_You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies, as explained below_ :

How to manage cookies

 **Google Chrome**

  * Click the spanner icon on the browser toolbar.
  * Select ' _Settings_ '.
  * Click ' _Show advanced settings_ '.
  * Under ' _Privacy_ ', click ' _Content settings_ '.
  * In the ' _Cookies_ ' section, you can manage your cookie settings.

 **Microsoft Internet Explorer**

  * Click ' _Tools_ ' on the browser toolbar.
  * Select ' _Internet options_ '.
  * Click the ' _Privacy_ ' tab, where you can manage your cookie settings.

 **Mozilla Firefox**

  * Click the ' _Firefox_ ' button, or ' _Tools_ ' at the top of the browser page.
  * Select ' _Options_ '.
  * Click the ' _Privacy_ ' tab.
  * Set ' _Firefox will_ :' to ' _Use custom settings for history_ '.
  * Manage your settings to accept or reject cookie types.

 **Safari**

  * Click ' _Safari_ ' at the top of the screen.
  * Select ' _Preferences_ '.
  * Click the ' _Privacy_ ' tab, where you can manage your cookie settings.

By continuing to use our sites and services you give your pre-informed consent to us using cookies (and other similar tools) on your visit. If you subsequently wish to revoke this consent, you may do so by deleting the cookies (and similar tools) via your browser tools settings. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our sites. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system may issue cookies when you log on to our sites.

If you want to learn more about cookies you can do so at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

##### 5\. WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, processed at and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will endeavour to take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy and Cookies Policy. By signing up to EmiratesSportlobster you agree to your data being transferred to, processed at and stored at, a destination outside the EEA by Emirates.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our sites; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

##### 6\. USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

We use information held about you in the following ways:

To ensure that content from our sites is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device.

To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. You may also unsubscribe by following the instructions contained within the notification or the instructions on our sites.

To help others find your account, including through third-party services and client applications. You can control this functionality through you account settings. You may choose to upload your address book so that we can help you find other users you know. We may later suggest people to follow on our sites based on your imported address book contacts, which you can delete from our sites at any time.

To provide features of our sites and services to improve and customize the services, for example, with more relevant content like local sports information, trends, stories, ads, and suggestions for people to follow.

To notify you about changes to our service.

To cross-post which helps us improve our sites and service.

To fulfil our legal obligations and respond to litigation.

For our statistical or survey purposes to improve our sites and communicate our services to you.

To prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our sites and enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

To send you information about our services or to market to you.

If you consent, to notify you by email of our products, promotions, competitions and special offers that may be of interest to you. You may use your account settings to unsubscribe from notifications from our sites.

To create non personally identifiable reports on the user interaction with our sites.

We may provide the information we collect from you to our partners. Both us and our partners may combine your information with other data with the objective of enhancing the offerings and experiences provided to you by us or our partners.

If EmiratesSportlobster ceases to exist Sportlobster will automatically convert all EmiratesSportlobster customers to Sportlobster customers and will notify you accordingly at the time.

##### 7\. HOW YOU CAN REMOVE, UPDATE OR CORRECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

_If you wish us to delete your details from our records entirely_ , you will need to contact us at [privacy@sportlobster.com](mailto:privacy@sportlobster.com) as we will need to do this manually for you. If you wish to delete your details from our partners you will need to contact them directly.

##### 8\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms and conditions and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
  * To our third party partners as part of providing the full functionality and services of our sites to you and to allow them to provide you with details of their services and/or products which might be of interest to you.
  * To our third party partners who cobrand versions of our platform with us, as part of providing the full functionality and services of our sites and offering to you. In such cases we may provide them with your information to allow them to provide you with details of their services and/or products which might be of interest to you. By using our sites and other services to consent to such processing.

##### 9\. MINORS

If you're under the age of 18 years and don't understand this Privacy and Cookies Policy please ask a parent or guardian to explain them to you. **In any case you must be 13 years or over in order to use our sites and services**. _You should not share any personal information with us if you are a Minor (the age of Minors is determined by local laws where you reside)_.

##### 10\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY

Any changes we may make to our Privacy and Cookies Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

##### 11\. LINKS

**_This Privacy and Cookies Policy applies only to information collected by us on our sites_**. _The sites may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy and cookies policies of such other websites and we would advise you to read the privacy and cookies policy of other websites that collects your personal information_.

##### 12\. CONTACT

If you have any questions, comments or requests regarding this Privacy and Cookies Policy, the practices of our sites and services or your dealings with our sites and services you can contact us by emailing [privacy@sportlobster.com](mailto:privacy@sportlobster.com).
